David Rodríguez Vindas

Mobile: +506 8377-9669 | Email: david.rodriguez13@hotmail.com | Costa Rica

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidrodriguezvindas

Professional Profile

Electronics Engineer with +20 years of experience collaborating in multinational environments in the technology industry. Software Verification Specialist, highly qualified in areas such as: process of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Agile (Scrum) Methodology, Assembled Test Equipment (ATE), Continuous Integration & Continuous Development (CICD), Integrated Development Environment (IDE), Applications Programming Interface (API). Tech savvy & AI driven executive, driven toward customer satisfaction and organizational goal.

Work History

Teradyne Costa Rica 2002 – 2024

Software Verification Engineer (STD)

2011 – 2024

Validate the ATE Software based on the test strategies and the customer requirement documents. Lead different projects related to various applications for products, such as: Digital, DC, AC, Microwave Instruments and DSP (Digital Signals Processing). Corroborate requirements of SW (Software) and HW (Hardware) for ATE Platforms. Create test plans and procedures, based on customer requirements. Review code among experts to ensure SW quality. Design, develop and debug programs, using Al-driven development methodologies (Copilot). Use (SCM) Software Configuration Management (ClearCase) tool used for version control. Execute programs in offline and online mode, looking for bugs prior integration. Automate manual tests using Perl scripts or Internal tools (APIs), to control graphical user interface applications. Create, debug, monitor, track and prioritize defects found during testing. Monitor defects in database to ensure SW stability and analyze the root cause (Jira). Work with different teams to ensure customer demands are met correctly. Maintain and support automated programs, running in a regression environment.

- Selected to be one of the presenters of the "Perl Automation Project" in Teradyne Technical Conference (TTC), Portland, Maine 2012.
- QA SW Lead Fourier Tier1 project, Teradyne Costa Rica 2013.
- QA SW Lead Fourier Tier2 project, Teradyne Costa Rica 2016.
- QA Lead IDP project, Teradyne Costa Rica 2018.

Test Technician at Global Customer Services (GCS)

2002 - 2011

Repair, troubleshoot and provide maintenance of the electronic equipment and boards. In charge of the repair process for systems such as: *Catalyst, J750, FLEX, UFLEX, Spectrum 8800 and 9100* series. Collaborate as a Team Leader for an average of 5 collaborators. Provide support in migrations during transfers of repair processes for different products from other countries such as: USA (Maine, California & Boston) and/or Philippines.

- Earn the "Value Star Award" by applying a different approach to solving a problem, Boston, MA 2004.
- Lead successfully the migration process/transfer for a *J750 MSO Board Option* from Teradyne Boston, MA to Teradyne Costa Rica in a 10-month period during 2004.
- Reduce the amount of *DOA (Death on Arrive)* boards by 60% and obtain the award for the *QIT (Quality Improvement Team)* from Teradyne Corp: "MSO Nightmare" Project. 2004.
- Transfer the *GEN4 system* Repair process, from Teradyne Boston, MA to Teradyne Costa Rica in a 11-month period during 2006.
- Transfer GEN4 system from Teradyne Costa Rica to Teradyne Philippines in a 3-month period during 2008.
- Transfer GEN5 system Apollo option from Teradyne Boston to Teradyne Costa Rica, in a 3-month period during 2010.
- Transfer Ai-760 board from Teradyne Boston to Teradyne Costa Rica, in a 3-week period during 2010.
- Finish Electronics Engineering graduation project. Create an automated Bench process (600% faster) for an old Manual test procedure, used to test\troubleshoot microwave modules "Athena", "Receiver", and "Nike", on Teradyne Costa Rica, during 2010 and 2011.

Previous Work Experiences

- Cafeteria Cootaxa Middle Level Manager | 2000 2002
- Restaurante Pollo El Rey Manager | 1997 2000

Formal Education

- Bachelor Degree in Electronics Engineering, Universidad Hispanoamericana, Costa Rica.
- Senior Technician in Electronics, Instituto Tecnológico de Costa Rica, Costa Rica.

Courses, Languages & Others

- Languages: Spanish (Native speaker) | English (CCCN / English Now Program Advanced)
- Technical Skills:

Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) | Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) | Quality Assurance | VBA (Visual Basic for Apps) | Visual Studio | Perl Automation | Automation API (Application Programming Interface) | Agile (Scrum) Methodology | AI-driven testing methodology | Microsoft Copilot | C | C++ | C# | .NET Framework | Visual Studio Code (IDE) | SQL | MySQL | Java | JavaScript | Jira | ClearCase | Test & Measurement Instrumentation | LabVIEW | ORACLE | TQM (Total Quality Management) | PDM (Product Data Management).

- Courses:
 - o IPC-A-610D normative Training.
 - 7 Step Training, Teradyne (TQM).
 - 5s Methodology, Teradyne.
 - o 1st aid & CPR training, Salva Corazones.